Lucas Fredegoto Rinaldi

Senior Full Stack Developer

Email: <u>lucasreinaldi@gmail.com</u> Portfolium: <u>rinaldilucas.com</u>
Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/rinaldilucas/</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/rinaldilucas</u>

Personal Statement

Working with information technology since 2014 and programming since 2016, I have contributed to incredible teams and been involved in projects and websites that have impacted millions of users. Always concerned with user experience and utilizing metrics to achieve the best retention rates, I am passionate about web development, especially the Angular framework. I actively work as a t-shaped professional, continually developing myself and my peers, contributing with excellence and experience in various contexts for which I am responsible.

Work Experience

> Forlogic — Senior Full Stack Developer, at Cornélio Procópio

May 2023 - present

ForLogic is a software development company focused on quality assurance, serving clients such as Unimed, BRK, and Cia Iguaçu.

- Inspection and correction of the improvement and bug queue for the software developed by the company using Kanban.
- Development and maintenance of internally consumed APIs for web apps and mobiles.
- Implementation of new features using Scrum.
- Author of a 500% improvement in build time, adding hot reload to an internal company library using npmjs.
- Responsible for defining and implementing lint (ESlint) and formatting (prettier) rules based on the Airbnb and Angular style guides, automating the code quality process.
- Code review for the squad.
- Deployment in staging and production environments.
- Migration and import of records from legacy modules to the new modules.
- Maintenance and manufacturing of migration and import tools.
- Responsible for coordinating and overseeing training for collaborators.
- Author of multiple tasks and workspaces for C# development using VSCode.
- Contribution to the squad with VSCode configurations focused on productivity.

> Slingshot Digital — Front-end Developer, at São Paulo

September 2023 - present

Slingshot is a web development producer that promotes solutions in campaign and platform development, serving clients such as McDonald's, HP, Samsung, Troller, and other brands.

- Page development from prototypes using PHP/laravel with Blade and handlebars.js with marionette.js.
- Development of new features for existing applications/for release.
- Facelifts and general layout changes.
- Estimation and definition of delivery times.
- Maintenance of the bugs queue of maintained projects.
- Metrics implementation and testing (Adobe Audience Manager, Facebook Pixel, Google Tag Manager).
- Using the Adobe package for image/video editing.
- Responsible for deployment in approval and production.

> Forlogic — Junior Full Stack Developer, at Cornélio Procópio

August 2019 - September 2020

- Migration of the organization's digital products from the MVC model to Angular, using REST API (C#) and Scrum as an agile methodology.
- Maintenance of the company's legacy product bug queue using the Kanban methodology.
- Development and maintenance of APIs consumed internally and offered as services.
- Creation and refactoring of unit tests using xUnit.

> Infinite Cloud — Junior Front-end Developer, at Londrina

September 2018 - January 2019

Infinite Cloud is a development agency focused on Marketing, promoting campaigns, and developing websites on demand, serving clients such as Unifil and PEC.

- Development of web projects such as e-commerce, institutional sites, portfolios, and websites in general.
- Consulting and monitoring advertising on Facebook and Google AdWords.
- Production, development, and artistic application focused on the web.
- Responsible for deploying and releasing the developed products.
- Testing and refactoring old code.

> **S4W** — Full Stack Trainee Developer, at Cornélio Procópio

September 2016 — February 2017

S4W is a marketing agency with web development, which carries out and launches campaigns and web development on demand, serving clients such as Aguativa, UTFPR, and Rotary Club.

- Web development from prototypes (Photoshop).
- Database maintenance (SQL server).
- Development and logical coding of projects (ASP.NET and C#).
- Refactoring and graphical improvements of existing projects.
- Testing and refactoring old code.

> **Town Hall** — Infrastructure Intern, at Cornélio Procópio

December 2013 - January 2015

The municipality of Cornélio Procópio has a technology sector, which helps internally and externally the needs related to the city's IT.

- Maintenance of hardware and software equipment used on the premises of the Municipality of Cornélio Procópio.
- Optimization and better use of physical computing resources.
- On-site and remote technical support.
- Assistance in the installation of the internal infrastructure.

> **Unimed** — Minor Apprentice in Operations, at Cornélio Procópio

May 2012 - May 2013

Unimed is a Brazilian medical cooperative system that operates as a health plan operator.

- Half of the working period to carry out courses such as administration, financial management, information technology, taxation, morals, duty, ethics, mathematics, communication, leadership, and logical thinking.
- Analysis and completion of documentation with a focus on digital innovation (migration from physical to digital system).
- On-site and remote operational support.

Academic Education

january 2014 - june 2017

Degree in Systems Analysis and Development

Federal Technological University of Northern Paraná – Cornélio Procópio, Paraná

Tech Stack

- Kanban/SCRUM - HTML5 - Git/GitHub - Linux - CSS3/LESS/ SASS - Protractor/Jest - Git Kraken/Git Flow - Windows - JavaScript ES5+ - Domain/Web host - REST/RESTful - macOS - ESlint/Prettier - Grunt/Gulp/Webpack 5 - Docker/AWS/GCloud - PHP/Laravel - Angular 2+ - NodeJS/Express.js/MongoDB - C# - XUnit/PhpUnit - Python - JWT/Auth middlewares - Marionette.js - Handlebars.js - Adobe XD - Photoshop/Illustrator - Figma - SEO

Academic References

Master Adriane Carla Anastácio

at UTFPR, Cornélio Procópio Campus anastacio@utfpr.edu.br

Doctor Luciano Tadeu Esteves

at UTFPR, Cornélio Procópio Campus luciano@utfpr.edu.br

Languages

- Portuguese (native) - English (proficient) - Spanish (basic)

Certifications

Several specialization courses focused on Development, Technologies and Leadership (\underline{see} certifications)

at Alura 2020 – present

Corporate Apprentice

at Unimed with CIEE/SENAC partnership 2012 – 2013

Specialization in Hardware, Web Design, Algorithms, Graphic Design, Administration

at CENAIC 2010 - 2012

Intermediate English, 480 hours

at CCAA 2006 - 2008